Eugene Sokolov

New York, NY

347.901.9097 eugsokolov@gmail.com eugsokolov.github.io

Full stack engineer with 5 years of software development experience in the financial technology industry looking to join a high growth team and solve interesting software/data problems. I enjoy designing robust systems and having my code automate!

Skills

Languages: Python (Flask/Django, pandas), SQL, NoSQL (Redis, Mongo), Javascript (Angular/NGRX, React/Redux, Node) Design: database design, automation, REST/RPC, git, Linux, AWS, Terraform, machine learning

Experience

Flatiron Health New York, NY

2020-

Senior Software Engineer

• Automating data pipelines for oncology research

The Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art New York, NY

2018-

Adjunct Professor (part time) - ECE 464: Databases

- Teaching a graduate level course exposing students to theoretical and practical applications in modern database development
- Topics include: relational data model, SQL, ORMs, database design, NoSQL, "Big Data"

Adaptive Management/Knoema New York, NY

2019-2020

Senior Software Engineer (fullstack)

- Develop, build, and support Oasis, an alternative data infrastructure and ETL ingestion system, processing TB of data daily
- Decreased client response times 1000x by redesigning an 'ingestion database' schema
- Develop, build, and support DataMonster, a data management and visualization Flask web application
- Increased productivity 20x by improving developer coding experience, PR processes, testing, and dev ops
- Spearheaded successful Python 2.7 to 3.8 transition (and increased test coverage)
- Increased QA productivity exponentially by managing a team of 6 contractors to build a Selenium regression test framework
- \bullet Increased revenue 15% by suggesting a major feature and wrote product specs, giving more fine grained introspection and control over charting tools
- Increased client usage and decreased download time 4x by refactoring Pypi library which provides API access to data

Hudson River Trading New York, NY

2016-2019

Software Developer (Series 57 certified)

- Monitored live trading weekly, tended to operational issues in a fast paced environment, and debugged mission critical software handling hundreds of millions of trades daily
- Worked with all areas of the firm to streamline company procedures and operational requests
- Developed, built, and maintained various Python processes and automated workflows
- Decreased corporate action issues 10x by automating procedures and improving override capabilities
- Created system to automate ETF order placement, managing notional values of \$1-10 million daily

Projects and Research

On Software Development Product Management: Feature Selection and Model Analysis of Predicting Jira Issue Attributes: Masters Thesis 2016-2017

• Researched Jira to determine factors that drive issue completion time, priority, and resolution using regression methods

The Influence of the Medial Prefrontal Cortex on a Socially Influenced Deception Task as Determined via Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation: 7th Annual Sense to Synapse Conference 2017

• Built programs for psychology experiments analyzing the medial prefrontal cortex and its affect on human social patterns

Wi-less Gauss: Senior Project Design

2016

• Created wireless glove-mouse as a computer mouse alternative, Fiverr Ingenuity Award at DreamIt.CodeIt.WinIt competition

Education

The Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art New York, NY

• Masters of Engineering (M.Eng.), Electrical Engineering 4.0 / 4.0

2017

• Bachelors of Engineering (B.Eng.), Electrical Engineering 3.5 / 4.0

2016